we refine the most of the castle today
that mustard castle they already kind of
read like so driving level one features
and so they can't be the other will use
their art and for for having a better
perception however we want we strongly
believe in vision and we are moving away
from using data at all the distance
horizon for the radar how far out can
the radar see right now well so that's a
limitation that can be a specifically to
calculate the cap one of the twenty
meters it's kind of like the meaning
with if gain saves at 120 when I'm
talking meter so it's like when I like
35 yards it's like the video that those
rather I can see but I mean like usually
they go up to 150 160 180 but then like
what use the purpose like sings so far
right it becomes like even if you see a
car when it's like 180 meters away
becomes very hard to understand you see
the cavities clips I'm like in my lane
or it's not like when it wins like so
far we know T if there is like a kukri
to all 180 meters away you won't see it
right the like you just care about
understanding where we objects are and
out of their object that they should
care about or not then when it gets so
far becomes like I don't like any port
okay it's a curiosity some look at the
what's the support cars I see Chevy bolt
and Prius which has you know has an
electric or hybrid drivetrain just kinda
curious is there any real difference
between developing open pipe or car that
uses an internal combustion engine
versus
it's the same what's up it's pretty much
the same like everything is the same I
just said like if we go back to the
slide about how a pilot works so pretty
much every Kenichi VC from half of these
and Beyond is the same except like you
power it is that by effect are you
generate like the plane so if you can do
this like imagine like well actually we
do make like we might change the way
that the for example you generate the
flaming if your characters along with
the basics but like except your
prerogative that define the size of your
car everything that comes before
controls is up started from the specific
car every things that come after
controls and have to do with interfacing
with your gamma can be scarce Pacific
and generally like go back to your
question how much does it change its
combustion engine or like leather cap
not really
we found that casts that are hybrid are
a little more pleasant to control
because I feel it matters does it softer
off like it is the combustion engines
um so what the thing that I'm thinking
about is and this is you know me and my
my craziest and doesn't have to do with
a lot with the self-driving car part but
with the the the the attention
measurement that you're doing you're
looking at the person's face yeah one
question I have is what's your method
right now doing that are you looking for
you start training on a baseline of you
know 80% of the time somebody's looking
in this orientation and so they deviate
from that for a certain period of time
and you sort of have a waiting algorithm
and finally when it trips you say okay
you're not paying attention because you
haven't been doing what you usually do
well so it's it's kind of like
abstracted like usually we found that we
iterated on the algorithm and we found
that actually people that pay attention
to their order they took straight your
hand is literally like kind of like like
thank you your eyes like your hand is
like perpendicular to today over them
yeah and we found that to be kind of
like the massed usable and best
indicator that makes the intention and
they makes it easy so what we do is like
we track like the angles like how your
head is oriented and then we have like
three shows over that depends like on
time for a longer you started and how
bad you like your to start out but
you're looking away and so we combine
all those things and we have some sort
of like lay shoulder to issue like the
war and it makes it easy because it's
not for now it's not going to dependent
for example life I like I like where
you're looking because for example like
if you have a glasses sunglasses still
works however we want to make it back
there and when possible start to track
Isis where you can
this is the system are really not meant
to be not suitable like if you wanted to
see if you can the point of this system
is that they should they should remind
you how you should be you should be
eight right and still it doesn't mean
that it should be should it be better
than what they are and so everyone like
if you don't have sunglasses you should
be able to try to track the ice movement
where your eyes are looking at and so
they are supposed to become better but
for now is like mainly like annotations
how far from from the what you are
looking for a lot and is that all that
module is that abstracted away from all
the rest of the open pilots stuff enough
to where you know you could install that
in a in a vehicle just to get those
alerts yes
so okay okay to clarify this is a very
good point I think you should topic type
IDs so they they come here which is like
the platform that we they are a platform
that we sell he by default doesn't
doesn't mean that doesn't drive your
cover it comes with the driver system
feature this is called passive tiger
system features so he warns you if you
are about to collide with the cars it as
for a collision warning and it has two
other monitoring it s like speed sign
recognitions things that we can just
leverage without having to interact or
like control your account in addition to
that can become a development kit that
you can install any software it's going
but the pilot which is the use of
software they can actually like to IDF
can actually but bots software starts
they are pretty much like very similar
to each other like the software that
comes before with the system and open
pilot they're very short each other
they're both open source and so yes you
don't need to have like a sister that
you drive your car she just wanted
futures care about like system it tracks
your intentions works as a dash cam so
of course your drive but what driving
driver like the older and the internal
of the car and so yeah you can
you don't need to use the specific
driving feature if you just care about
the Monaco features and are there any
sensors that you're reading off of the
canvas that you absolutely have to have
there or there so you could actually
have a complete separated from any of
the electronics of the car is still
getting some of that
well yeah you should use TV and wiring
at least yeah monitoring for sure on a
speed sign of course because I can just
rely on like GPS like we have like GPS
like what open apps obvious like man he
was obviously mad no it's like let's say
level level one like like here's step
one is like you just you just have to
hear like in your car and it's not
connected to the can system of your of
the car and it just works as a dashcam I
still like dude a diaper monitoring if I
were cuz your warning
that's all worse that's that too is like
but you have a supported car you're
connected to can see TV you don't take
advantage of the driving features but
things are going to be better because
you take care of like you know exerted
by the speed of the carrier's etc then
the next step after these it's like when
you actually is lot of the pilot you
have this is too much really okay okay
so sort of like you can get like 25
things from from the system was that
sorry if I miss that you know I didn't
say action
so in some cities with poor
infrastructure such as Albuquerque you
may have noticed some of the places you
can barely see lane markings and street
signs are missing or knocked over stuff
like that how well will the software
Adela learn to adapt for things like
that are you just gonna have to take
over anytime that the city you're
driving and it has been infrastructure
well so we do I know for example we are
relying on the lane lines quite at least
okay kind of the right without lane
lines but it doesn't work like a job
yeah it's getting back there so it's
getting over the time is getting better
it's getting like it is let you realize
less and less on the actual feature like
being pressed like pretty much like at
you but that's a chemical driving if you
don't say yeah one of us are driving and
there's no lines we can kind of
extrapolate from where everyone else's
yeah exactly so right now I would say
like it kind of depends on like for
example I clean lines safely but I don't
know I came down route 66 there's a park
that have no lines for probably
quarter-mile and identified the sand one
side of the right line just the color of
the dirt out here Apple to do that yeah
we were teaching the system to identify
a license just abstract it from a
specific line line Caesar but the next
release is like
and so-and-so
what Soviet rip just cast away with
Megaten
and it's an ongoing process I believe
that as of now we still have to do some
more homework and like making the system
better but like in parallel yes we will
be open to discuss we have done in the
past we want to keep doing it but yeah I
think they're usually two people
homework it should be a good path yes
University supported vehicles the
different different cars have different
lower speed limits where they lose
steering their acceleration
functionality is a sense of limitation
or actuators and DC is that improving or
the cars getting better the figure is
getting better the point is that so
certain cars like we have to make it
with the cats so we are like MSL
everything is kind of abstracted from
the car but then at certain point the
last the end is like a dependent and so
we have to obey to attack there are
their constraints of the specific car
hands so if the specific cars locks you
are for controlling like the brake
giving to steal for example below 10
miles per hour then there's nothing we
can do about that unless we last visited
like change the former of your cameras
which we don't want to do and instead
like the point of an Impala should be
really like creating something that ok
has to deal with limitations that can
have a car specific at the same time the
important thing is that open pilot
itself is capable of handling that
situation we care about vocabulary
pilots like a software that can is
actually up started and very general and
then of course like Africa is so
limitation
which is that we are forced to pay to
them but the more we move forward the
lastest limitations are our present
because cars that cheap now are less
limited and Catholic worship like a year
ago or two years ago like every car
pretty much liked by the for tends to
add adaptive cruise control we stop and
go so it means that they can't braking
and gas controllable from zero speed to
whatever speed like 90 100 110 miles per
hour so the directions get definitely
like more capable cars which we actually
stop early align that with the
capability of the pie yes but as the the
data streaming app I can how
standardized is that from one model to
the next or sensor specific sensor to
the next so like if you're reading let's
say speed data or for or radar how
drastically different is it from a
Toyota to a BMW or ever okay well so
among they they open source repositories
between ever like when pilot is one of
those repositories like software
software market where you can find like
a complete complete like set of features
we have we have another of the social
positive the disco like open D BC where
so the DBC file is that the file that
describes your your can your CAD data
this times are your candidate are like a
structure right and so this is like our
specific mainly car make and then within
a car make almost every car are very
similar with each other we have like so
you mentioned I have one file per car
those files are all very similar to each
other within the same car maker they are
the last
for anything for different car makes so
the DBC fight for Tata
Excel yeah but she's like another
project that we have again we are
reverse engineering this like can
communication and we understand ourself
what things mean cool well thank you
guys so much for coming we have a mobile
store if you are interested in
purchasing a tour t-shirt that's one of
a kind only can get on this tour we also
have the Aeon that Ricardo talk about
some sweatshirts and will be around if
you want to ask those questions we got
Eddie Harold myself and